So we did get our slice of the state here and output it with the ctr props,
now I also want to be able to dispatch actions
and for that, we need to find out how we can also dispatch actions from within our components.
Now when we just use redux in standalone, we simply called dispatch on the store.
Now we don't have access to the store in our container at least not directly,
we got access through connect though
and just as we were able to pass some information about which kind of state or which slice of the state
you want to get, we can also pass a second configuration,
I'll name it mapDispatchToProps because here I'll say which kind of actions do I want to dispatch
in this container.
This also stores a function which will receive the dispatch function which we can execute as an argument,
just as we have dispatch available on the store here,
if we directly access the store, the react-redux package gives us well basically this helper function
which will call dispatch on the store behind the scenes.
We then here also return a javascript object where we can define some prop names which will hold
a reference to a function which should eventually get executed to dispatch an action.
Now you can choose any property name you want here, I'll name it onIncrementCounter,
but again, the name is up to you.
This property now holds a value of course and that value should be an anonymous function,
so here I'll use a ES6 arrow function like this
and I'll use the very short version where if it's written in one line, the part on the right side of
the arrow is automatically returned.
So here, I want to return a call to dispatch
and this is the call, what I want to do here,
this function here will in the end be available through this property and therefore, whenever this property
is executed as a function,
for example, if we assign it to an onClick handler, then this dispatch method here is going to get executed.
And to this method, I can now pass a javascript object where we need to set up a type
as you learned and I'll set the type to increment here. With that, we got a property we can also use in our
container,
well at least we can do so when we pass it as a second argument to connect.
And by the way, if you ever have a case where you don't have any actions in your container, you just leave
it out as we did before or if you have a container which only needs to dispatch actions but doesn't
need a slice of the state, you'll simply pass null as the first argument to connect,
just as a side note.
So back to our set up though, now I'm passing mapDispatchToProps to the connect method too
and with that, I get access to the onIncrementCounter method here.
So let's use that property,
I'll copy the name onIncrementCounter and I want to use it here in my counter control, where I
have the increment button. Here right now on the click prop which is just a prop I passed the reference
what I want to execute onClick down to counter control, so I can pass a function which should be executed
when I click to this prop. Here,
I now want to pass no longer this anonymous function but this onIncrementCounter, without executing
it
so without parentheses, just like this.
This will then refer to this prop which holds a reference to this anonymous function which will then
be executed which will then dispatch this action. With that we're dispatching an action,
now let's also see how to changes this the counter by going back to the reducer
and of course adjusting it to handle this action.
So here, I'll add an if statement to check the action type, like that and I'll see if the action type is equal
to
and now I need to take the same identifier as specified here because that is of course the identifier
identifying this exact action,
so one typo and it won't work.
So I'll copy the increment text and I'll check for the action type being equal to that, inside of here,
I then want to return my updated state immutably by creating a new javascript object and I don't even
need to copy my old states here
first, though we could do that,
for now, I'll simply return a new object with the counter property because that's the equivalent to copying
everything because we only have the counter property in our old state anyways.
So here, I'll return counter and set this equal to state.counter plus one, like that.
So with that, the reducer is set up, if we go back to the counter container, make sure onIncrementCounter here should dispatch
this action.
Now if we have a look, oh here's here's a mistake by the way, clicked where we refer to onIncrementCounter,
this of course is not a class method as it would have to be if we call it like this,
it's passed via props.
So this.props.onIncrementCounter is correct because it's just a property we receive, a property holding
a reference to this function.
Now with these changes in place, if we save everything, save all files and go back to the application, we'll
see that none of these buttons
does anything but the increment button does, it increments the counter but now managed through redux.
This is awesome,
now let's practice this a bit.