The where are you successful Let's solve that together.
And for that let's first of all quit and start and install the two packages we need whether it be dash
dash save and then it's read X and re-act redux.
These are the two packages we need to hit enter to download and add them to your node modules folder.
And once this is done you can restart NPM start.
Now of course we want to use these packages and for that first of all create a new folder in my source
folder the store folder and then there I'll create my new reducer Doug as fall.
I don't really need to split this into multiple producers here because we only have one feature adding
persons.
So there are even different areas in this app we will work with multiple reducers again.
Once you work on the course project again.
So this is the one producer we add it now here how do we set this up in the reducer fall.
I want to create an initial state does this the state we start with in this app.
Its a javascript object where we have a persons array which is empty just as the initial state in the
person's container here.
Then we have our producer function and I'll use to ESX function syntax.
You can of course also use to erase five syntax.
You are all named as producer and we get two things.
We get the state and we get the action which was dispatched and the status initially set to initial
state.
Now inside Daedra to use for function on now add a switch statement where I switched the type property
on my action.
I receive and remember typed is not optional you contrie rename this type is expected by the redux package.
And then I want to do different things for adding and deleting users before I had this.
I'll export my reducer here.
Export this as the default of this file.
Now for the actions all create actions dodgiest follow.
This is optional.
You could also work with hardcoded string.
I did the fires but to reduce the risk of mistyping all UCD export at Constans and the actions fall.
I'll have one for adding a person and you can name this whatever you want.
I'll give it a identifier of ADD person and one for removing a person hence also getting an identifier
of remove person.
That's all in my actions.
J.S. fall.
I can now import this in my reducer So there or import everything from does actions fall as action types
from dot slash actions and then I want to check the two different cases I'll have.
I'll have the case that I have the action type at person when to return my updated state here.
I'll then have the case that we have action types.
Remove person and also return my updated state to your and in all cases I want to return my old state.
So that is at the end just not inside but outside of the switch statement therefore now with this set
up the reducer is kind of finished well.
We're not doing anything with our ad person removed person events here.
But there's something I will add soon before I add it let me add or connect my re-act up to you to state.
So in the index yes fall I'll import two things I'll import something from reader X and I'll import
something from re-act relax.
Do you know what well from relax it's create store and from re-act redux.
It's simply the provider component now all wrap my root app component with my provider component here
and then I need to create my story.
So create a new constant store maybe or whatever you want to name it and execute create story and to
create store I need to pass my producer so so import my producer here reducer from that slash store
reducer.
This is now what it has to create store.
Now with that past our application is generally connected.
And we got the store which is created by the redux package.
Now of course we need to fill our producer with some life.
We already have the logic in our persons container.
All get rid of the estate there but I can take the logic from the person added handler and person deleted
handler.
I'll put it into my reducer.
So your person added I create a new person.
And no I don't call said state.
Instead here I return a copy of my old state here.
Theoretically that wouldn't be needed since we only have the person's property.
But imagine you have more properties you don't want to kill these other properties.
So copy all the properties and then override the person's property with the state persons.
And now concat the new person to it just as we did before locally in the container component.
And now I can't get rid of this sad state here and the producer of course doesn't make sense here.
Now I just have to new person which I concat to my persons aere thus creating a new array which replaces
the old person's sorry.
Now for a remove person I can also copy the logic from there.
Actually I can't just copy the folder logic here go back into the producer and then return a copy of
my old state properties and Zeff person's equal to state persons and now change the folder.
Call now here I expect to get the idea of the person which should be deleted and I expect us to get
this on my action.
So action per snidey all have to make sure that we pass this ID along with the action when we dispatch
it.
That's the finished producer with that in the container component we can simply delete person added
handler and present delete that handler.
Now here on person added an on clicked.
We now want to instead dispatch our actions so first of all let's import the actions so import everything
as action types or whatever do you want to name it from the store folder.
From the actions file there.
Just like that.
And now with that I can create these two new constants.
Map state 2 props to get access to my state and map dispatch to props to get action access to these
dispatched the dispatch function and be able to dispatch actions.
I'll start with mapping States to prop's as you learned this expects to hold a function which will receive
state as an input passed into the function automatically by redux and in the function body.
Here we should return a javascript object where we map a slice of our X state to something we'll be
able to access as a property in our container or component.
So there I want to have let's say a property P R S.
You could name it persons or just don't name it like this to make it really clear that it's not the
same as our state.
So P R S could be mapped to state and there the persons property.
Now here you have to make sure that you of course spelled a property name here exactly as it's spelled
in the reducer So if that we get access to the persons in our container component.
Now for map this page to props we all store a function in this constant a function which receives the
dispatch function as an input and then here we all the return object where we map props to dispatch
function executions.
And here I map my property for adding persons and deleting persons.
So maybe on ad a person could be an anonymous function where I call this patch in the end.
And now I dispatch action types add person and I'll add another prop on removed person here.
I also dispatch action types.
Remove person but here I also need to pass a payload and generally important.
This has to be a javascript object so you don't just pass the string as an argument.
You pass a javascript object with the type of death string.
That's a common gotcha you get wrong set to type here in the javascript object and the type that is
your action type still for removing a person just passing the type isn't enough.
We also have to pass the idea of the poorest.
We want to remove.
So I expect to get it id as an argument in this function so that I can then pass whatever I expect in
the reducer in this case person idea as a property on the action so that I pass per ID here by setting
that property in the object dispatch equal to the ID I receive here.
And now we just have to use that correctly in our component GSX code for adding persistence and simple
is simply execute.
This props and so on added person for deleting.
I will still use an anonymous function as we did before to Den X-ists dis prop's on removed person and
still press the prison ID as an argument so that it reaches dysfunction here.
This ID and we can dispatch it with dead.
We're managing everything from Rydex.
We connected the dispatch functions with props and our state.
Let's now see if it works that save all the false and we see that we get carried read persons of knol.
So on our state we fail to read this.
Well the reason is of course in the container component to the persons I map here still refer to this
state persons.
That doesn't exist anymore we deleted this.
Instead we should take this p r s argument on the prop's not on the state.
So this props P R S is now correct.
Now with dad if we save it and we go back we reload the application.
We still get error or do you know why
well we defined map state to props and map dispatch to props.
But what are we not doing.
We're not informing our component about these constants.
Just adding the concepts like this doesn't do anything.
We need to connect our component to our state with DS to constants with DS functions to constants hold
in the end as arguments and for that you'll learn that we can import something from re-act read X and
conveniently this something is even named.
Connect.
So we import the connect function from re-act redux and then we add it down there to the export and
pass map state to props.
So this constant here as the first argument and then map dispatch to prop's So this argument here is
constant here.
Rops as the second argument and then you learned that connect with these two arguments returns a function
which we also execute and where we pass the person's component to.
And now with that we got our container connected.
But if we go back to the index file you'll see that once we wrap our app component with the provider
and we do create a store with create store.
We never make the final step of passing death's door to a provider because of course that's coming from
two different packages so we have to make that connection and we do that by adding the store property
on the provider and setting it equal to the store constant which holds a reference to the store we created
with create store.
And now with that if we save all the files we have a running application again where we can click at
person and remove the persons and as you see it removes the correct one.
So that's the assignment solved.
A little bit of redux and re-act redux practice.